Seize your glory!
300: Rise of an Empire is a action, drama, war film directed by Noam Murro.
Greek general Themistocles attempts to unite all of Greece by leading
the charge that will change the course of the war.
Themistocles faces the massive invading Persian forces led by mortal-turned-god,
Xerxes and Artemesia, the vengeful commander of the Persian navy.
Themistocles, played by Sullivan Stapleton.
Artemisia, played by Eva Green.
Queen Gorgo, played by Lena Headey.
Scylias, played by Callan Mulvey.
Dillios, played by David Wenham.
Xerxes, played by Rodrigo Santoro.
300: Rise of an Empire is a 2014 American epic historical action film directed by Noam Murro from a screenplay by Zack
Snyder and Kurt Johnstad, based on the then-unpublished comic book limited series Xerxes by Frank Miller.
A sequel to 300 (2006), it takes place before, during, and after the main events of that film, and is a
fictionalized retelling of the Battle of Artemisium and the Battle of Salamis in the Greco-Persian Wars.
The cast includes Lena Headey, Peter Mensah, David Wenham, Andrew Tiernan, Andrew Pleavin, and Rodrigo Santoro reprising
their roles from the first film, alongside Sullivan Stapleton, Eva Green, Hans Matheson, and Callan Mulvey.
300: Rise of an Empire was released theatrically
on March 7, 2014, by Warner Bros.
It received mixed reviews, with critics praising the action sequences, music, cinematography, visual effects and
Green's performance but criticizing the story, Stapleton's performance, and overstylized gore.
The film was a box-office success, grossing $337 million
worldwide from a $110 million budget.
The film explores themes of based on comic, sword
fight, soldier, massacre, slow motion.
The tone is emotional and intense.